What are some uh TRT clinic red flags?
Because that's very important to a lot
of guys coming into the groups and
newbies to this channel.
>> I'm going to give you the big picture of
what a red flag is to me and then I'm
going to dive into the the micro details
of why that is a red flag. The biggest
red flag to me as a provider of
testosterone to thousands of men around
the country is when someone is on TRT
through a provider who accepts health
insurance.
Not to say that the fact that you accept
health insurance necessarily means that
you're doing things differently, but it
always turns out to be that way.
Providers who accept insurance are paid
in a model where they have to do volume.
You literally cannot make a living as a
provider if you're seeing a low volume
of patients on a day-to-day basis. If
you're seeing one to two patients per
hour with insurance, you cannot make a
living. All insurancebased models
operate on a 30 to 50 patient a day
scenario. And you only get paid for the
office visits. So, they have to drag you
in. By definition, providers who are
insurance-based or credentialed with
insurance companies for reimbursement do
not optimize the level of studying
and research and clinical experience and
literally building their entire practice
around dosing hormones correctly for
men. And the reason for that is that is
not what pays their bills. That is a
small portion of where they actually
make their living. The big part of where
they make their living is other areas of
medicine.
And because of that they will never do a
good job compared to someone who
literally just focuses on this one
aspect who is a subsp specialist of the
specialty.
Us as subsp specialists we cannot accept
insurance because insurance doesn't pay
us what we need to be paid in order to
do the job that we do for the amount of
people that we do it for. So, a provider
who accepts insurance by definition of
the way the system is designed will not
do a proper job on men's hormones. So,
insurance-based providers, first red
flag for me. Second red flag, even with
all the testosterone clinics that are
cashbased,
if they check things like estrogen or
estradi in a man, they clearly do not
understand the intricacies of
endocrinology versus introinology versus
metabolites or exogenous hormones or how
all of this plays together. So, if they
test your estradile, it is a red flag.
If they prescribe, and I don't care if
they don't prescribe it to you, and I
don't care if they said only use it if
you need it, and I don't care if they
said you don't need it for now, but you
may need it in the future. If they ever
wrote a prescription to any man for an
aromatase inhibitor,
they are completely clueless about
anything to do with man's hormones. You
need to leave that clinic immediately.
Even if they don't force it on you, if
it is in their repertoire, they are a
bad clinic. Period. End of the story. We
can spend the next hour explaining why
we won't do it here, but we have plenty
of videos on this. So again, they
prescribe an aromatase inhibitor to
anyone. Garbage clinic. Period. End the
story. Um, so don't test estrogen, don't
block estrogen. Those are the two big
ones. If you're seeking insurance based
providers, you're going about this the
completely wrong way. Uh, those are
probably the top red flags. Uh if they
have a guideline of numbers where they
say if your total tea is here you
qualify. If it's here you don't qualify.
That's utter nonsense because they're
chasing numbers. If they make you donate
blood every two months, three months,
four months continuously and an ongoing
neverending cycle. Terrible clinic. Get
out fast. Um, if they try to prescribe
you, you know, a dozen different
medications to counteract side effects
from the other medications they give
you. If they prescribe you anabolic
steroids like aone and an angelone and
all this other, get out. They are a
money grab. They are a steroid clinic.
They are not going to look out for your
health. You may feel great initially.
You're gonna shorten your lifespan and
you're going to run into a slew of
problems down the line. So unfortunately
all of the things I just mentioned are
the norm and the commonality in this
industry. All red flags. All red flags.
Terrible.